wordfly.com 2014-11-22

# Privacy Policy :: WordFly.com

#### Effective: September 17, 2014

Privacy is serious business to us—especially when you are entrusting WordFly with your subscriber data. If we had to sum up this page in one sentence we'd say: We are 100% committed to protecting the privacy and data of you and your subscribers. But here's the long version, because this information is important.

## Definitions

This web page describes the privacy practices of “WordFly”, a product of POP, Inc., regarding the collection and use of personal or corporate information that you provide to us through the Web site located at www.wordfly.com and app.wordfly.com, however this website is accessed and/or used, whether via personal computers, mobile devices, or otherwise. Please be advised that the practices described in this privacy policy apply only to information gathered online through the Website.

By visiting our Website, you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this privacy policy, please do not use the Website.

  * The terms "We," "Us," and "WordFly" refer to POP, Inc. (“WordFly”), a Washington corporation.
  * WordFly,(the “Website” or "Application"), is an online system developed by POP, Inc. for creating, delivering, and tracking digital communication campaigns (the "Services").
  * The term "WordFly" refers to either the business or the online system as the context requires.
  * When an "Organization" signs the WordFly Terms of Use, we will set up an "Account" for that organization. Each "Account" can have an unlimited number of registered "Users".
  * “You or “Your” refers to a person who is reading this Privacy Policy and is registered to use WordFly.
  * Any and all digital communication sent out using WordFly is referred to as a "Campaign"
  * "Subscriber Lists" are lists of email addresses and mobile phone numbers imported by an organization into WordFly to which they would like to send a campaign through WordFly. "Subscribers" are people contained in these lists. Supplemental information that may be imported about these subscribers, such as First and Last Name, is referred to as "Subscriber Data".

Pop, Inc. has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) and the [TRUSTed Cloud Program Requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/TRUSTed-cloud/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at support@wordfly.com. If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request).

The TRUSTe program covers the collection, use and disclosure of information we collect through our website: [www.wordfly.com](http://www.wordfly.com/) and our service, WordFly. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which the Client has engaged Pop, Inc.

Pop, Inc. complies with the U.S. - E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. Pop, Inc. has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Pop, Inc.'s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

## Types of information we gather

### Personal Identifiable Information you provide to us

When you register as a new user with WordFly or email customer support, you provide us with personal identifiable information that we collect, such as email address, first and last name, job title, and phone number. By providing us with this information, you consent to your information being collected, used, disclosed, and stored by us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

WordFly collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. WordFly works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected.

We may also collect personal information from you under the following circumstances:

  * When you sign up to receive email newsletters from us
  * When you request additional information, customer service, or other assistance
  * When you participate on social media accounts involving WordFly properties

### Non-Personal Information we collect when you interact with the Website

When you interact with the Website, our servers may keep an activity log that does not identify you individually. Generally, we collect the following categories of Non-Personal Information:

We collect and store certain device information about your computer, or other device that you use to access the Website by storing strings of code called “Cookies” on your computer. This information may include IP address, browser type, browser language, and other transactional information.

We automatically log certain usage information about your use of the Website. This information includes a reading history of the pages you view. We use this information to provide you a more customized experience on the Website.

We collect and store additional "traffic data" such as time of access, date of access, software crash reports, session identification number, access times, and referring website addresses.

We also collect and store certain other information regarding our users' use of the Website so that third parties may provide us reports and analysis regarding usage and browsing patterns of the Website.

### Information related to campaigns you send

Any email addresses, mobile phone numbers, and supplemental subscriber data that is imported by you into WordFly for use in a campaign you have sent or are going to send is stored in WordFly. We also store all information that is used in a campaign you have sent or are going to send. After the campaign is sent, we store who opened, clicked, bounced, and shared the campaign.

### Benchmark reporting

If your organization chooses to opt in to the Benchmark Reporting datashare program, we will take data created through your use of WordFly, remove all identifiable information about your use of WordFly, and then combine that data with anonymous data from other organizations in comparable industries and offer benchmark reports in an aggregate form. This data includes your industry, industry category, region, open rates, click rates, and bounce rates from your campaigns.

## How we use and disclose your personal + non-personal information

### To communicate with you as a WordFly user

  * Account Maintenance. We use your email address to uniquely identify you when you log in and to communicate with you about your account. You will receive an email from WordFly when you are added as a new user. If you forget your password, we will email you instructions for how to reset your password.
  * System Alerts. You may be sent brief system alerts to let you know about planned updates to the system that may affect your account.
  * WordFly User News. We send a monthly email announcing new features, learning opportunities, and information about how to use WordFly. From time to time we will also promote other POP product offerings. You can unsubscribe at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the email. 
  * Customer Support. We use the email address you provide to us to communicate with you about customer support issues and feedback about WordFly. 
  * Billing. If you are the billing contact for your organization, we will send you invoices, receipts, and notices of delinquency related to your account via email.

### Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy.

### To service providers

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as customer support. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

WordFly may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

### To meet legal requirements

  * If required to provide such information by a court, administrative or governmental order, or subpoena or other legal process.
  * If required to provide information to people helping us comply with legal and other requirements such as attorneys and accountants.

### To detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may be illegal or violate the WordFly Acceptable Use Policy

From time to time we look at the content of email campaigns sent through WordFly in order to ensure that the Acceptable Use Policy is followed. This is necessary to help prevent spam, ensure compliance with data privacy and anti-spam legislation, and ensure higher deliverability for all campaigns sent through WordFly.

### To transfer your information in the event that we change our ownership or corporate organization while providing the Website.

As a result, please be aware that in such event we may transfer some or all of your Personal Information to a company acquiring all or part of our assets or to another company with which we have merged. In such event, your Personal Information may be subject to a different privacy policy, which we will make available on our Website.

### For publicity purposes

As per the WordFly Terms of Use, you agree that POP may use the name of your organization, your organization's logo, and your organization's publicly available information (such as email templates) for our PR and marketing efforts.

## Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by POP and our analytics providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies for [our shopping cart, to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference), for authentication]. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

We use Local Storage Objects (LSOs) such as HTML5 to store content information and preferences. Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)) Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

## How we use and disclose your subscriber data + lists

Except as disclosed below, we won't ever contact, share, or sell your subscriber data + lists. Your subscriber data + lists belong to you. They can be exported at any time from WordFly. We will only contact a subscriber on one of your lists in response to a complaint or if a subscriber has contacted us directly.

### To meet legal requirements

  * If required to provide such information by a court, administrative or governmental order, or subpoena or other legal process.
  * If required to provide information to people helping us comply with legal and other requirements such as attorneys and accountants.
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so.

### To detect, investigate, and prevent activities that may be illegal or violate the WordFly Acceptable Use Policy

From time to time we look at the content of email campaigns sent through WordFly in order to ensure that the Acceptable Use Policy is followed. This is necessary to help prevent spam, ensure compliance with data privacy and anti-spam legislation, and ensure higher deliverability for all campaigns sent through WordFly.

### To transfer your information in the event that we change our ownership or corporate organization while providing the Website.

As a result, please be aware that in such event we may transfer some or all of your Personal Information to a company acquiring all or part of our assets or to another company with which we have merged. In such event, your Personal Information may be subject to a different privacy policy, which we will make available on our Website.

### To support and improve the services we offer

Including adding features and providing benchmarking and other comparison information based on aggregating and analyzing data.

### Information from other sources

For reporting purposes, we may use a subscriber's email address to obtain additional information that appears to be related to the email address, such as a name and whether the subscriber participates in social media websites. This information may be obtained by searching the Internet directly or through one or more services.

## How we secure your data

### What we do

  * WordFly requires an account name, username, and password to log in.
  * Your password and security question answer are encrypted and known only to you. We cannot see your passwords. We can only reset them. If you forget your password, you will need to reset it in WordFly by answering your security question correctly.
  * Any data that WordFly sends or receives is electronically encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL) when sending over network resources. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. The WordFly web application and associated mail systems use safeguards that greatly reduce the risk of a security breach, DOS (denial of service) attack, and other Internet-based attacks. 
  * Dedicated support staff and monitoring systems track the security and overall health of the WordFly services.
  * WordFly services are protected by redundant enterprise-grade firewalls that are monitored 24/7/365.
  * In addition to the security offered by our hardware and software manufacturers, we perform frequent security testing and auditing of all of network and server systems.
  * The WordFly servers are hosted in a Tier 1 datacenter with on-site security guards, video surveillance, and a highly restrictive access system. 
  * Each WordFly client uses their own database, reducing the amount of data that could be breached at any one time.
  * Users are automatically logged out after 60 minutes of inactivity
  * A very small group of carefully screened and trusted employees of POP have access to subscriber data + lists.

### Your responsibilities as a user

  * Click the Sign Out link in the upper-right corner of WordFly when you are finished using WordFly to prevent unauthorized access from your computer.
  * Remove users when they no longer work at your organization.
  * Maintain the confidentiality of any account name and password provided to you. You are solely responsible for uses of any account provided to you, whether or not authorized by you.
  * Immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your account.
  * Use the Secure Upload link provided inside WordFly if you need to send sensitive data, such as subscriber lists, for troubleshooting purposes.

### If a breach occurs

  * In the event that a security breach that affects you and your subscribers occurs, we will notify you as soon as possible via the email address you provided to us. We will follow-up with information about what steps have been taken to rectify the security breach.

## Links to Other Web Sites 

Our Site includes links to other Web sites whose privacy practices may differ from those of WordFly. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any Web site you visit.

## Social Media (Features) and Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

## Blog

Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at support@wordfly.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

## Data accuracy + your rights

We store your Personal Information exactly as it was entered by you or a colleague at your organization. You are responsible for notifying us of any changes to your data to ensure that your data is current and accurate. If you would like to update or delete your personal information or if you would like to delete/deactivate your account with WordFly, please contact us by emailing our Customer Support at support@wordfly.com or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below.

We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

WordFly has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, who seeks to correct, amend, delete inaccurate data or withdraw consent to further contact should direct his/her query to WordFly’s Client (the data controller). If the Client requests WordFly to remove the data, we will respond to their request within 30 days.

If you would like to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails, please follow the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails or you can contact us at the contact information listed below.

We collect information for our clients, if you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by one of our Clients that use our service, please contact the client that you interact with directly.

You are the owner and are responsible for all data (including graphics, content, email addresses, and other personal information of your customers) you add or upload to the Website. Except as described above, POP will never use, sell or distribute the data that you own.

We agree to temporarily store your data on the Website during the term of the WordFly Terms of Use. In the event the Terms of Use is terminated, we will permanently delete all of your personal information, email templates, assets, content, campaign results, and all related data and files from our Website.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

WordFly will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. WordFly will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

## Effective date + notice of changes

This Privacy Policy is effective with regard to all data that we have collected or collect from you, both before and after you registered as a User, in accordance with the WordFly Acceptable Use Policy and WordFly Terms of Use.

POP may modify the provisions of this Privacy Policy from time to time. Any changes will be posted to this Website. The new provisions will be effective as soon as they are posted or the notification email is sent. Your continued use of the Website following posting of the changes will mean that you accept those changes. If we make any material changes, we will send a notification of the changes to all WordFly Users to the email address provided to us when they registered prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

## Questions + Comments

We'd be happy to answer questions you might have about our Privacy Policy. In addition, if you have concerns or wish to update or delete any of your personal information stored in WordFly, please contact us via postal mail or email us via our contact form.

POP, Inc.  
Attention: WordFly Privacy Department  
1326 5th Ave  
Suite 800  
Seattle, WA 98101  
USA

Phone: 206-728-7997
